RENÉ GABRIEL CRUZ MUÑOZ

Finance Manager

rencrumu@gmail.com

+56 9 64157171

Finance professional with over 20 years of experience in a multinational company, having worked in Chile, Netherlands and United States of America.

I have developed a wide range of Finance roles from Business Controller to Corporate Finance, engaging with multifunctional and multicultural teams, providing me a strong strategic thinking, discipline and the ability to adapt myself to different scenarios, merging my financial skills with the business needs for tangible results.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

2016 - 2022

Philips Electronics North America, United States of America, Image Guided Therapy (IGT) Senior FP&A Manager

Supported the post-merger integration of 2 new businesses into Philips, helping the new acquisitions to be onboarded into the Philips standard processes and business model. Controlled a 200M integration budget.

Structured productivity initiatives to support the cost savings and re-investment programs by measuring the financial impact of the different projects. Developed a financial tool to measure, prioritize and control productivity initiatives by translating into financial indicators the productivity achievements.

Developed tools and processes for the budgeting, forecasting and reporting of the new business created in Philips from the integration of the 2 new companies (IGT Devices - USD 1B revenue).

2011 - 2016

Philips International B.V., Netherlands, Group Control Senior FP&A Manager - Reporting & Consolidation - Project Manager

Modeling the financial targets for the Philips Group: Comparable Sales Growth, Adjusted EBITA Margin and Average Working Capital. These targets are used to measure performance and annual incentives. Financial analysis and reporting to Philips' Executive Committee, including presentations for investors calls and roadshows.

Improved the Group's budgeting process through the Lean Thinking practice by reducing waste and leveraging quality.

Consolidating the Group's P&L statement, ensuring high quality reporting under IFRS and Functional Cost reporting analysis.

Project Management of the Philips Annual Report, including cost budgeting and control, program management, content discussions with the Group's CEO and CFO, multifunctional teams coordination, meeting IFRS disclosure requirements and SEC reporting standards.

2001 - 2011

Philips Chile, Consumer Lifestyle & Corporate Area Head of Finance & Business Controller

Leading the Corporate organization and its Enabling Functions (Finance, IT, HR, Real Estate, Purchasing and Legal).

Ensuring Business Compliance with the General Business Principles.

Leading Corporate Finance and Accounting, including month end closing and reporting, treasury management, audit management and Enabling Functions controlling.

Finance Business Partner for Consumer Lifestyle (USD 70M business), including commercial support and analysis (Price Management, Customer Profitability and business controlling).

Lead the development and implementation of a new Customer Service model that improved the Service Net Promoter Score from -15% to +35% while reducing cost and increasing forecasting accuracy.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND:

UC San Diego - California - USA, 2020 Lean Six Sigma Black Belt

Universidad Adolfo Ibanez, E-Class, 2012 IFRS

Universidad de Chile, Santiago - Chile, 2007Business Intelligence

Universidad Central, Santiago - Chile, 1996 - 2001Bachelor of Business - Business Administrator

LANGUAGES:

Native language: Spanish Other languages: Fluent English

PERSONAL DATA

Date of birth: May 2nd, 1975

Nationality: Chilean

Marital Status: Married, 1 son and 1 daughter.

Residence: Santiago, Chile.

www.linkedin.com/in/rene-cruz-munoz